Joshua Philipp Entrop

Krukmakargatan 60, 117 41 Stockholm · Phone: (0046) 76 255 20 58 Email: Joshua.Philipp.Entrop@stud.ki.se

Introduction

I am a master student with passion for health data and statistical analyses. My research interests are not limited to certain diseases or health issues. Instead, I am interested in statistical and methodological challenges that come along with a variety of research topics. Within the research process, the phase of data analysis is the most interesting one for me. I love to apply different statistical models to data, to reveal new insights, which cannot be seen at first glance. Therefore, I am always working on enhancing my R programming and statistic skills. Given that background, I am currently searching for PhD position in the field of applied biostatistics and epidemiology.

Curriculum Vitae

Scholarships	
09/2019 - 06/2020	Scholarship holder, German Academic Exchange Service (DAAD)
04/2016 - 06/2020	Scholarship holder, Friederich-Ebert-Foundation
Academic Education	

09/2018 - 06/2020

Candidate in Public Health Epidemiology (M.Med.Sc.), Karolinska Institutet, Sweden

Preliminary master thesis title: Type 2 diabetes mellitus risk in individuals with and without sarcoidosis stratified by corticosteroid treatment: a matched cohort study using Swedish registry data

Focus:

- Statistical analyses (especially flexible parametric survival models)
- Study design
- Methods of data collection

04/2015 - 05/2018

B.A. in Social Science, Ruhr-Universität Bochum, Germany Grade: 1.2 (Passed with Distinction, best graduated student in 2018)

Bachelor thesis title: Economic, social, cultural capital and disease. An empiric examination of Cockerham's Health Lifestyle Theory based on Data of the ALLBUS 2014

Focus:

- Statistics
- Research methods
- Medical sociology

Additional Training

Data Scientist with R, DataCamp

To evolve my R programming skills I went through the extensive Data-Camp's Data Scientist with R track. The programme includes multiple online courses on R programming, data cleaning, data management, data analysis and data visualisation using R.

School Education

07/2006 - 06/2014

Reinoldus und Schiller Gymnasium Dortmund, Germany High-School Degree (Abitur), Grade: 1.8

Specialized courses:

- Social Science
- Mathematics

Working experience

06/2019 - 07/2019

Research Intern, National Taiwan University, National Burden of Disease Centre

My responsibility at the National Burden of Disease Centre was to estimate the health burden of alcohol consumption in Taiwan using the global burden of disease framework. For this I combined Taiwanese data sets with data on relative risks from the burden of disease study. A major part of my internship was to implement all these calculations using the statistic package R.

04/2017 - 07/2018

Teaching Assistant, Ruhr-Universität Bochum, Faculty for Social Science, Social Policy and Social Economic Section

As a teaching assistant at the Social Policy and Social Economic Section my responsibilities were to conduct and plan weekly seminars with 15 to 20 students in addition to the lecture "Introduction to Micro- and Macroeconomics". Additionally, I was also responsible for the administration of the Moodle online courses for these seminars.

08/2017 - 10/2017

Research Intern, NRW Centre for Health, Health Assessment and Forecasting Section

During my time as a research intern at the NRW Centre for Health I was responsible for the estimation and prediction of the type 2 diabetes incidence for Germany and the region of North Rhine Westphalia (NRW) from 2013 till 2023. All these estimations were carried out using the statistic package R.

Languages

German: Native Speaker

English: C1 CEFR Swedish: A2 CEFR

IT-Knowledge

R, STATA, Latex, SPSS, MS Office

Voluntary Activities

08/2018 -	Speaker of the scholarship holder's working group in health of the
	Friederich-Ebert Foundation
08/2014 - 08/2018	Engaged in communal politics in the municipality of Dortmund, Ger-
	many

Joshua Entrop

Stockholm, 2020-04-22